headcount.org 2011-12-09

# Privacy Statement | HeadCount | Register to Vote!

**HeadCount will not share your personal information with anyone.** The information you voluntarily provide when signing up for HeadCount’s mailing list or online community is used exclusively for updating individuals on information related to HeadCount, voting, and non-partisan political issues. You may receive email or other communication from HeadCount for this purpose.

Upon being added to HeadCount’s mailing list or online community, each person for whom an email address is available will receive an email that includes information on how to unsubscribe. If at any other time you decide that you would like to stop receiving HeadCount’s email or other communications, you may click the unsubscribe link on future emails or send an e-mail to info@HeadCount.org requesting to be removed from the HeadCount database.

## HeadCount Voter Registration

Should you register to vote using HeadCount’s online voter registration tool, the information you provide will be administered according HeadCount’s Privacy Policy and the privacy policy of the software provider, whose policy is provided to anyone using that software. This policy states that by using the software, you grant the software provider and HeadCount permission to use your personal contact information to send you communications. The software provider’s full policy is available [[here](http://www.rockthevote.com/voter-registration/online-application-system/privacy.html)]. You can unsubscribe at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions on the communication itself.

Personal information and other unique identifiers required by law for voter registration applications, including but not limited to those submitted through HeadCount, either at an event or through our online voter registration tool, becomes a matter of public record and is available for inspection and use by legitimate candidates for public office and their campaign organizations as well as by others who qualify under the applicable State or local laws.  
On a selective basis, HeadCount will provide this publicly-available information with partners and other organizations with principles and/or missions that overlap and are consistent with those of HeadCount, for the purpose of educational activity aimed at increasing voter turn out. Anyone who completes a voter registration application through HeadCount but prefers not to have their voter registration information used in this manner may opt out by sending an e-mail to [donotcontact@headcount.org](mailto:donotcontact@headcount.org) within 10 days of competing their voter registration application. Individuals who opt out should send an e-mail to this address that includes their name, e-mail address, the date on which they registered and the location (either specifying an event, or noting that they registered on-line).

## **Text Messaging**

If you opt-in to our mobile community, standard text messaging charges will apply. To unsubscribe, text back "stop" at any time.

## **Legislative Action**

HeadCount’s legislative action web pages enable you to easily write to elected officials, and require you to enter your contact information. By using this service, you consent to joining the HeadCount community and HeadCount mailing list and will be afforded the same protection, services and communication as any other individual on the HeadCount mailing list. Should you wish to not remain on the HeadCount mailing list, simply click “unsubscribe” on any email you receive or email [info@headcount.org](mailto:info@headcount.org).  
On certain occasions, HeadCount will partner with other organizations to stage joint legislative actions. In some instances, personal information will then be shared with the partner organization, but ONLY if that is clearly stated on the legislative action page, with a link to both organization’s privacy policies.

## HeadCount's Volunteer Effort

HeadCount is run by volunteers. By agreeing to be a volunteer you consent to provide certain information. Some of that information is required, while other information may be optional. Your volunteer information can be edited at any time. By entering this information you will be added to HeadCount's mailing list, under the terms HeadCount’s **Privacy Policy**. Your personal information will never be sold or shared. You reserve the right to terminate your volunteer status with HeadCount at any time.

## Security

HeadCount takes all reasonable steps to protect personal information and uses technology such as encryption, access control procedures, and firewalls. By using this website you agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. Without limitation of the foregoing, you understand and agree that (1) the information collected by HeadCount may be stored indefinitely, (2) HeadCount may store, access and use the information in any jurisdiction, including jurisdictions in which the privacy laws may be different and less protective than those in your home jurisdiction and (3) HeadCount may collect, process, use and disclose the information for a variety of purposes, including, without limitation, voter registration and volunteer coordinating.

## Legal Compliance

Notwithstanding anything else stated in this Privacy Policy, HeadCount reserves the right to disclose your information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is reasonably necessary to (1) comply with legal process, (2) respond to any claims against it, or (3) protect the rights, property or personal safety of HeadCount, our users or the public.

If you have any questions or comments about our use of personal information, please contact us at [info@headcount.org](mailto:info@headcount.org). We will respond with speed to any issues regarding your privacy.

HeadCount shall not be liable for any direct, indirect, consequential or exemplary damages of any kind, including, but not limited to, lost revenues or profits, loss of business or loss of data, or for any claim, loss or injury based upon errors, omissions, interruptions or inaccuracies in the information housed at or linked to this site.

**Links to third-party websites  
**HeadCount’s website contains links to other third-party websites. HeadCount does not guarantee the accuracy or timeliness of, endorse the opinions of, or take responsibility for the information provided. The views expressed on any such websites do not necessarily express the views or opinions of HeadCount. These links are provided for informational purposes only. ****  
**Your Acceptance of These Terms**  
By using HeadCount’s website, you accept HeadCount’s Privacy Policy.

HeadCount reserves the right to update or change this Privacy Policy at any time to clarify or improve or policy. Changes will be posted to this webpage and the “Last update” date will reflect the date of the most recent changes. Your continued use of HeadCount’s website following the posting of such changes to the Privacy Policy constitutes acceptance of those changes.
